## Contact

jnaude60512@gmail.com LinkedIn GitHub

# Top Skills

Time Series Forecasting Machine Learning Python

## **Certifications**

- Time Series Analysis, Forecasting, and Machine Learning
- Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp
- Higher Certificate in Information Systems (Software Development)
- Calculus I
- Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp with R

### **Public Contributions**

- viss
- <u>SimpactCyan</u>
- <u>spatialedge-analytics-dfauditor</u>
- holidays
- LG-WebOS-Remote-Control
- MacbookPro14-2Ubuntu

# Jean Naude

# Machine Learning Engineer at Spatialedge

Stellenbosch, Western Cape, South Africa

# **Summary**

Senior Machine Learning Engineer with 5 years of experience in developing, deploying and optimizing machine learning models and taking them to production for large retail chains based in South Africa. Co-Founder of a non-profit that played a key role in developing open-source software for an international epidemiology simulation project that provided valuable insights to the World Health Organization

My strength lies in getting to production quickly with observable, impactful results that facilitate business decision-making

# Experience

## **Spatialedge**

Machine Learning Engineer

Stellenbosch, Western Cape, South Africa June 2021 - Present (4+ years)

Technical Lead Engineer on two enterprise data applications that provided highly optimized results in the retail and financial sector. Mentored junior engineers, provided technical guidance and engineered technical foundation for both projects

Productionized and contributed to 8 Machine Learning models providing high-value insights to the retail and financial sector

Models: Lead Time Forecasting, Demand Forecasting, Interbranch

Transfers Optimimization

Apps: Workforce Planning Optimization, Cash Replenishment Forecasting

and Optimization

Frontends: React, TypeScript, CSS, GrapQL

Backends: Ruby, Postgres

DevOps: CI/CD, Gitlab, GCP, Terraform

#### Exile AI

(Founder) Full-Stack Engineer

Cape Town, Western Cape, South Africa January 2024 - Present (1+ years)

Engineered the first open source Viral Infection Simulation Subsystem (VISS) that provided valuable insights to the World Health Organization. Established roadmaps for 4 new open source projects that hold potential to significantly contribute to improved health and economic outcomes. Modularized both front-end and back-end. Back-end is open source and open to contributions. Developed technical infrastructure for a large non profit medical clinic

Backend :Redis DB, C++, Crow(API), CUDA Frontend :React, TypeScript, CSS Tailwind

# **Education ESIEE PARIS**

International Masters in Computer Science

#### **Pearson Institute**

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

2015 - 2018

## Tech Stack

Python

Pytorch

• Scikit Learn

• C++

CUDA

• C • SQL

• Big Query

Bash

• Git

 Docker CI/CD

GCP

Airflow

Dagster

Tensorflow

• Redis DB

Kubernetes

Terraform

• Helm

 React • TypeScript

• Gitlab

• Linux

## **Interests**

- Epidemiology
- Computer Vision
- 3D Printing
- Home Automation (using HomeAssistant)
- Puzzle Games
- Musical Theory